# Howie Hao Wang

#### **About Me**

A web designer and developer with a background in architecture.

My interest in tech started with work experience at WeWork. I was fascinated by how a data-driven approach is implemented in design. Later at SOM, I worked on an interior project involving VR. In my spare time, I self-taught programming and gradually realized my true passion for web development.

My diverse background prepares me with both design and develop skills:

A keen eye for design; professional experience using design tools; solve real-world problems by design thinking, research and analytical skills.

\*1. <u>watch a self-introduction video</u> to get to know me.

\*2. watch a portfolio presentation to better understand how I worked on my projects.

# **Education**

#### University of Virginia

Aug. 2015 - Dec. 2017 | Charlottesville, VA Master of Architecture, GPA: 3.61, Scholarship Recipient GRE: 319 \*Full score in Math.

## University of Mining and Technology

Sep. 2010 - Jul. 2015 | Xuzhou, China Bachelor of Architecture, GPA: 3.89, Rank: 2/86, Full Scholarship Recipient

#### Software Engineering Student

Mar. 2021 - Current | at Udemy HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React, Redux, NodeJS, Express, Python, PostgreSQL, MongoDB, Flask, Jest

Completed courses, total 277.5 hours in length:

Next.js & React: The Complete Guide Jan. 23, 2022

React: The Complete Guide

Dec. 30, 2021

Node, Express, MongoDB Bootcamp

Sep. 20, 2021

The Complete JavaScript Course 2021 Jul. 15, 2021

Build Responsive Real-World Websites Sep. 8, 2021

The Complete 2021 Web Development Bootcamp Apr. 9, 2021

howiewang2020@gmail.com

(1) 434-227-8996

howiework.com

github.com/HowieWork

# **Projects**

#### Snap App | MERN-stack web application

Share, navigation, architecture, plan. Snap App focuses on creating a photo sharing platform for people who love architecture. Inspired by real-life experience as an architectural designer. Read full story of Snap App.

#### **Lunch Break** | Built with Next.js & MongoDB

A blog site cares about work-life balance focusing on design, psychology my interest in tech started with work experience at WeWork. I was fascinated by how a data-driven approach lished since launching. Read why and how I built Lunch Break.

#### React Guide | Built with React

I am currently working on my own guide for React including general components, patterns, interview questions.

# Howiework | Built with React; Hosted by GitHub page

I completely redesign and rebuild my portfolio website using React. It is a major update from <u>previous design version</u> for my aspiring dev career.

## Museum - NMAAHC | UI/UX design project

A mobile app design for a museum. Goal is to enhance visiting experience. Personal product project contains the whole process including UX research.

\*Below is a list of tutorial projects. I am currently working on adding more features and customizing these projects. Stay tuned!

# Natours | Built with Node, Express, MongoDB

A web app for helping people choose where to travel in North America.

## Forkify | Built with HTML, CSS, JavaScript

Search over 1,000,000 recipes. Find your favorite recipe and bookmark it.

## Mapty | Built with HTML, CSS, JavaScript

An app maps your workouts. Built with OOP, Geolocation API, Web Storage API.

# Experience

#### Work

## Freelance Designer / Developer

Mar. 2020 — present | Washington DC

Help clients rebranding; build portfolio sites with Wordpress/Squarespace. Worked on projects like Snap App, NMAAHC mobile app redesign.

#### Product Designer / Developer

Jul. 2019 — Mar. 2020 | Remote

Worked on MIAO product. Helped customer successfully rebrand their product, website using JS, HTML, CSS and integrate with their store-front design.

# Architectural Professional at Skidmore, Owings & Merrill LLP (SOM)

Jun. 2018 — Jul. 2019 | Washington DC

Involved in an interior office HQ Project: work on SD, DD, CD; Worked closely with market team and clients. Integrated VR into presentation.

## Architectural Intern at WeWork

Feb. 2018 — May 2018 | New York, NY

Worked closely with professions from tech background. Implemented data-driven design approach and research on space & profit efficiency.

## Research & Volunteer

Moon Village Jan. — Jul. 2019 | New York, NY

SOM research project (collaborating with Europe Space Agency and MIT) Lumina Pavilion (UVa Bicentennial Celebration) Sep. 2017 — Oct. 2017

## Skills

#### Programming languages

JavaScript, HTML, CSS, Python

#### **Tools & Platforms**

Git, MongoDB, Firebase, Vercel, Netlify, Heroku, Wordpress

#### Frameworks & Libraries

React, Next.js, Node.js, Express

#### Design

Figma, Adobe XD, Adobe Creative Suite (Photoshop, InDesign, Illustrator)